northwest.com 2011-11-10

# Northwest.Com -::-

## Privacy Policy

## This is the website of NORTHWEST.COM

**Postal Address:**  
7150 SW Hampton Street   
Suite 202  
Tigard, OR 97223

| 

**Email:**  
info@northwest.com

| 

**Phone:**  
503-639-2727  
  
---|---|---  
  
### Privacy Protection

This policy establishes how NORTHWEST.COM handles the information we learn about you when you visit our site. Protecting the privacy and personal data of our visitors is of utmost importance to us. Protecting your privacy and your personal data is an essential aspect of the way we create, organize and implement our activities on-line and off-line. Our website follows the principles set out in the Recommendation of the Council concerning Guidelines Governing the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Flows of Personal Data (C(80)58/FINAL).

### Purpose Specifications and Data Collection

In general, you can browse the NORTHWEST.COM website without disclosing any information about yourself. If you visit the NORTHWEST.COM website to read or download information, we collect and store only the following information that is automatically recognized: the date and time, the originating IP address, the domain name, the type of browser and operating system used (if provided by the browser), the URL of the referring page (if provided by the browser), the object requested and the completion status of the request. For more details on this data and the reason why we log it, please see Information automatically recognized and logged.

### Cookies and Other Technologies

As described above, we sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our website to help us provide better customer service. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit and we also measure visitor activity on the NORTHWEST.COM website, but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. We use the information that we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different areas of our site and to help us make our website more useful to visitors. This includes analyzing these logs periodically to measure the traffic through our servers, the number of pages visited and the level of demand for pages and topics of interest. The logs may be preserved indefinitely and used at any time and in any way to prevent security breaches and to ensure the integrity of the data on our servers.  
Also, when we collect personal data from you in connection with a transaction we may extract some information about that transaction in an anonymous format and combine it with other anonymous information. This anonymous information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patterns. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, you can either disable your cookies or opt-out at the order or request stage.   
We collect the personal data that you volunteer on registration for such actions as registrations, surveys, competitions, forms or by email.   
We do not associate the information stored in a visitor's cookie with any other personal data about that visitor.  
All our employees and processors who have access to personal data and are associated with the processing of that data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of data.

### Visitor's Choice

Registering on our website is optional. If you choose not to register or provide personal information, you can still use NORTHWEST.COM Website. However, you may not be able to download certain documents or access certain areas of the website. NORTHWEST.COM views the customer information that we collect as a valuable and confidential asset and we take great care to ensure its safety.  
You may choose to register to NORTHWEST.COM and receive promotional or marketing information from NORTHWEST.COM by selecting the appropriate option when you register personal data. If you choose to register, your information will be available to NORTHWEST.COM staff and to delegates for the purpose of events management. If you do not wish to continue receiving promotional or marketing information, please notify us.

### Security

We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your personal information. NORTHWEST.COM has implemented technologies and security policies to protect the stored personal data of our users from unauthorized access, improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. We will continue to enhance our security procedures, as new technology becomes available. NORTHWEST.COM employees and processors who have access to personal data are obliged to respect the privacy of our visitors and the confidentiality of their personal data.

### Notifications of Changes

As NORTHWEST.COM creates new services that may generate a need to amend this privacy statement, NORTHWEST.COM will highlight such changes on this page as appropriate.
